<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>52p52w on anurags blog</title>
    <link>/tags/52p52w/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 52p52w on anurags blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Anurag Saxena</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/52p52w/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>52 posts in 52 weeks: result</title>
      <link>/post/52-posts-result/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/52-posts-result/</guid>
      <description>At the end of 2017, I decided to make blogging a part of my life of 2018. I decided that I will be writing 52 posts, which is a post a week. And hence, 52 posts in 52 weeks was born.
It’s the end of 2018 and I published 18 posts (not counting this post). 18 is less than 52, but better than 0.
The year started off with a post a week, but I quickly fell behind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Creating a new file or folder in NerdTree</title>
      <link>/post/til-creating-a-new-file-or-folder-in-nerdtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/til-creating-a-new-file-or-folder-in-nerdtree/</guid>
      <description>To create a new file or folder in NerdTree, bring up the NerdTree menu by typing m. This brings up a multiple options including:
(a)dd a childnode (m)ove the current node (d)elete the current node (r)eveal in Finder the current node (o)pen the current node with system editor (q)uicklook the current node (c)opy the current node (l)ist the current node So now you press a and can type in the file name or the folder that you want to create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Vote</title>
      <link>/post/go-vote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/go-vote/</guid>
      <description>Its Election Day in America. Go Vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest in Index Funds instead of stocks</title>
      <link>/post/invest-in-index-funds-instead-of-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/invest-in-index-funds-instead-of-stocks/</guid>
      <description>You don&#39;t have the time or the energy to follow stocks, which ones to invest, which ones to not. When to invest, when to take money out. Instead, invest your money in Index Funds.
There is a saying that a monkey throwing darts on a board with stocks can beat the market. That is because stock performance is difficult to predict. You can predict overall market easier than individual stock market performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the boring thing</title>
      <link>/post/do-the-boring-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/do-the-boring-thing/</guid>
      <description>that is all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts I listen to regularly</title>
      <link>/post/podcasts-i-listen-to-regularly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/podcasts-i-listen-to-regularly/</guid>
      <description>Here are the podcasts that I listen to regularly, and recommend to folks who want to listen to something new.
 Up First - NPR - my go to podcast every morning Monday to Friday. Catch up on the top headlines and news for the day in about 13-15 minutes. Freakonomics Radio The Indicator from Planet Money - NPR Pod Save America Radiolab Star Talk Radio - recently started listening to it and loving it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcast.fm</title>
      <link>/post/overcast-fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/overcast-fm/</guid>
      <description>Overcast is a podcast player that is available on iOS to listen to podcasts. I have been using overcast since 2015 and I have loved it. I stopped using it and switched to the stock Podcasts app on iOS for a minute when I could not get the podcasts on my watch, but then I switched back when watchOS allowed for Overcast to play podcasts directly on the Apple Watch - which is a game changer for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Allegany State Park</title>
      <link>/post/hiking-in-allegany-state-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hiking-in-allegany-state-p/</guid>
      <description>Few weeks ago, my wife and I went camping at the Allegany State Park in New York. This is a year round park - meaning that its open all year around for campers and visitors alike.
The park is huge at 64,800 acres. This was our first time here and we enjoyed the stay. Our cabin faced this tiny creek which was beautiful.
Being that this park is also bear country, we had to be mindful of our belongings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pydoc</title>
      <link>/post/pydoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pydoc/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk recently at the Cleveland Python Meetup on pydoc. Here is the notebook explaining it all: https://github.com/CLEpy/CLEpy-MotM/blob/master/pydoc/pydoc.ipynb</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dont wait. Just do it</title>
      <link>/post/dont-wait-just-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dont-wait-just-do-it/</guid>
      <description>On August 11, 2018, this tweet went out.
On this day ten years ago, Airbnb launched. pic.twitter.com/UFA7b1weRh
&amp;mdash; Brian Chesky (@bchesky) August 11, 2018  Look at the screenshot. Look how rudimentary the site looks. Yet AirBnb was started. And now its worth a billion dollars.
Dont wait for the right idea to come in your head. Just do it. You will fail. But after failure will come success. Just do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git stash</title>
      <link>/post/git-stash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-stash/</guid>
      <description>Git stash allows you to save your changes to a repo, without any commits, and go back to the clean state that your repo was in since the last commit. I use stash when I have to pull changes from origin into my code, but I don&#39;t want to commit any of my own changes. Stash allows to manage merge conflicts as well. You can use stash when you want to switch branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Github Acquisition</title>
      <link>/post/microsoft-github-acquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/microsoft-github-acquisition/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts  $7.5 billion is huge. A big part of that number includes value of open source projects. It is the open source projects that made Github what it is and brought the community together. Github made people recognize their potential, by having their work be shared and collaborated on an open, free platform. $7.5 billion is huge. Microsoft paid good money for this acquisition. I do not know what the ultimate goal is here, but it is an investment into the future of Github, and I am cautiously optimistic - just like a lot of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Merge</title>
      <link>/post/how-i-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-merge/</guid>
      <description>Stage the files
git add &amp;lt;files&amp;gt; Commit the files
git commit -m &amp;quot;&amp;lt;message subject&amp;gt;&amp;quot; -m &amp;quot;&amp;lt;message body, if needed&amp;gt;&amp;quot; Pull the master
git pull origin master Merge any conflicts and commit. Then,
git push origin master Profit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook</title>
      <link>/post/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/facebook/</guid>
      <description>I joined facebook in 2007. Before that, I used to interact with friends on Orkut. I joined facebook because my friends told me to.
Facebook was quite innocent when I joined. I was friends with people on Facebook that I was friends in real life, and I would see them every now and then, if not more. Then pages came along, and I started liking facebook pages. Friends started to invite me to like a page, and I would do the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longing for a consumer upgradable Macbook Pro</title>
      <link>/post/longing-for-a-consumer-upgradable-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/longing-for-a-consumer-upgradable-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>My first Macbook was a 2011 Macbook Pro (MC700LL/A). It came with a 4GB of RAM and 320 GB HDD. After 1.5 years of use, I was able to upgrade the RAM to 8GB and swap out the HDD for a 512 GB SSD. The performance upgrade was life changing. The effort was minimal. Just unscrew the back panel using a precision philips screwdriver and with little knowledge, one can swap out the RAM and HDD/SSD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I switched to Ghost</title>
      <link>/post/i-switched-to-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/i-switched-to-ghost/</guid>
      <description>As you can see, I switched to ghost. If you go to my first post, I talked about how I wanted to use posthaven and how it is great.
 I am using posthaven over medium, or blogger, or wordpress, is because of its simplicity. You can read much about posthaven here: https://posthaven.com/ . It has an easy posting format, lets me use my own domain and I can even email my posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India 2018</title>
      <link>/post/india-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/india-2018/</guid>
      <description>I love coming to India. It is the country where I am “really from”. It is where I grew up. But, I have not been living here 9 years now, and every time I visit, I see new things. I see how the country is advancing, and I see where it lacks behind.
The smartphone market has exploded in India with everyone holding a smartphone. You can even hail a rickshaw with your phone, which is great - because I hate to haggle on fares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don&#39;t know what to write about</title>
      <link>/post/i-dont-know-what-to-write-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/i-dont-know-what-to-write-about/</guid>
      <description>I am not motivated enough to write this week. I am being lazy.
It&#39;s Tuesday. Day 2 of the week. I want to keep on the schedule of writing at least one post a week, but I have not had the chance to work on an article. The next two and a half weeks I will be traveling to India, so the posts will be from India and about India. This week is all about preparing for the travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to not use an ad blocker</title>
      <link>/post/when-to-not-use-an-ad-blocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/when-to-not-use-an-ad-blocker/</guid>
      <description>I use an ad-blocker on my browsers. Its called ad-block plus.
The good part of using an ad-blocker is that it blocks the ads on the sites I visit. It also helps with blocking malware, spam, and cookies that track over websites (you know how when you search for shoes on zappos and then that shoe ad shows up on every website you visit).
The bad part of using an ad-blocker is that there are websites that are solely run, or are majorly dependent on ad revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>52 posts in 52 weeks (atleast)</title>
      <link>/post/52-posts-in-52-weeks-atleast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/52-posts-in-52-weeks-atleast/</guid>
      <description>I have been wanting to do this for a while - blog. And by a while, I mean for years now. I try, and then I am not so comfortable about it, and things come up, and I give up. It is easy to give up. There is no direct immediate cost to giving up. There are other, easier things to do.
But why write? Why blog? Well because writing is a means of recording information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>