<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anurag&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anurag&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Anurag Saxena</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Azure AD SSO with SAML for your FastAPI Application using PySAML2</title>
      <link>/posts/azure-ad-pysaml2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/azure-ad-pysaml2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had to work on a Azure AD SAML integration for a FastAPI application.&#xA;I looked around the internet for a how to and stitched together a solution from&#xA;multiple sources. I am writing this post as a how to on integrating Azure AD SAML&#xA;SSO into a FastAPI application so that there is a single source for others to use.&#xA;I am using PySAML2 and I am sure there are better ways to do this but this is how&#xA;I did it. This integration is written for a FastAPI application but since PySAML2 is&#xA;a library seperate from the Web Framework being used, you could use this as a guide&#xA;to integrate PySAML2 with Flask etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software Developer in Cleveland, OH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#PEP 20&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passwords should be disposable</title>
      <link>/posts/passwords-should-be-disposable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/passwords-should-be-disposable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Passwords should be long - as long as you want to make them. The longer the password, the bigger its entropy. Mathematically, guessing the password &lt;em&gt;sallysallysally&lt;/em&gt; will take longer computing time than &lt;em&gt;sally.&lt;/em&gt; Websites or apps that ask for 8-16 character passwords should not be asking for a max character limit of passwords. Instead they should encourage users to create long passwords. Also, do not restrict the user to only use certain special characters - let them use all of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>52 posts in 52 weeks: result</title>
      <link>/posts/52-posts-result/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/52-posts-result/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2017, I decided to make blogging a part of my life of 2018. I decided that I will be writing 52 posts, which is a post a week. And hence, &lt;strong&gt;52 posts in 52 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s the end of 2018 and I published &lt;strong&gt;18 posts&lt;/strong&gt; (not counting this post). 18 is less than 52, but better than 0.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The year started off with a post a week, but I quickly fell behind. Part of the reason was motivation, the other is that writing is hard. During this process, I realized that in order to write more, I have to read more. So I started reading more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Creating a new file or folder in NerdTree</title>
      <link>/posts/til-creating-a-new-file-or-folder-in-nerdtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/til-creating-a-new-file-or-folder-in-nerdtree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To create a new file or folder in NerdTree, bring up the NerdTree menu by typing &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt;. This brings up a multiple options including:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(a)dd a childnode&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(m)ove the current node&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(d)elete the current node&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(r)eveal in Finder the current node&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(o)pen the current node with system editor&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(q)uicklook the current node&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(c)opy the current node&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(l)ist the current node&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So now you press &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and can type in the file name or the folder that you want to create.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Vote</title>
      <link>/posts/go-vote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/go-vote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its Election Day in America. Go Vote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invest in Index Funds instead of stocks</title>
      <link>/posts/invest-in-index-funds-instead-of-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/invest-in-index-funds-instead-of-stocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or the energy to follow stocks, which ones to invest, which ones to not. When to invest, when to take money out. Instead, invest your money in Index Funds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a saying that a monkey throwing darts on a board with stocks can beat the market. That is because stock performance is difficult to predict. You can predict overall market easier than individual stock market performance. That is where Index Funds are a better investment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do the boring thing</title>
      <link>/posts/do-the-boring-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/do-the-boring-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;that is all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts I listen to regularly</title>
      <link>/posts/podcasts-i-listen-to-regularly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/podcasts-i-listen-to-regularly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the podcasts that I listen to regularly, and recommend to folks who want to listen to something new.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/podcasts/510318/up-first&#34;&gt;Up First - NPR&lt;/a&gt; - my go to podcast every morning Monday to Friday. Catch up on the top headlines and news for the day in about 13-15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://freakonomics.com/&#34;&gt;Freakonomics Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/podcasts/510325/the-indicator-from-planet-money&#34;&gt;The Indicator from Planet Money - NPR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crooked.com/podcast-series/pod-save-america/&#34;&gt;Pod Save America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wnycstudios.org/shows/radiolab&#34;&gt;Radiolab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startalkradio.net/&#34;&gt;Star Talk Radio&lt;/a&gt; - recently started listening to it and loving it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimletmedia.com/startup&#34;&gt;Startup Podcast&lt;/a&gt; - If you do not know about this podcast, I recommend you start with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimletmedia.com/startup/1-how-not-to-pitch-a-billionaire#episode-player&#34;&gt;Season 1&lt;/a&gt;. Season 1 of this podcast is about how to start a podcasting company.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tim.blog/podcast/&#34;&gt;Tim Ferriss Show&lt;/a&gt; - top episodes here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tim.blog/top-10-podcasts/&#34;&gt;https://tim.blog/top-10-podcasts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always Overcast is my go to podcast app. &lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/&#34;&gt;https://overcast.fm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcast.fm</title>
      <link>/posts/overcast-fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/overcast-fm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/&#34;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast player that is available on iOS to listen to podcasts. I have been using overcast since 2015 and I have loved it. I stopped using it and switched to the stock Podcasts app on iOS for a minute when I could not get the podcasts on my watch, but then I switched back when watchOS allowed for Overcast to play podcasts directly on the Apple Watch - which is a game changer for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Allegany State Park</title>
      <link>/posts/hiking-in-allegany-state-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/hiking-in-allegany-state-p/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few weeks ago, my wife and I went camping at the Allegany State Park in New York. This is a year round park - meaning that its open all year around for campers and visitors alike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The park is huge at 64,800 acres. This was our first time here and we enjoyed the stay. Our cabin faced this tiny creek which was beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being that this park is also bear country, we had to be mindful of our belongings. We locked our food either in the cabin, or in the car. We never left food outside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pydoc</title>
      <link>/posts/pydoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pydoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk recently at the &lt;a href=&#34;clepy.org&#34;&gt;Cleveland Python Meetup&lt;/a&gt; on pydoc. Here is the notebook explaining it all: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CLEpy/CLEpy-MotM/blob/master/pydoc/pydoc.ipynb&#34;&gt;https://github.com/CLEpy/CLEpy-MotM/blob/master/pydoc/pydoc.ipynb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git stash</title>
      <link>/posts/git-stash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/git-stash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git stash allows you to save your changes to a repo, without any commits, and go back to the clean state that your repo was in since the last commit. I use stash when I have to pull changes from origin into my code, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to commit any of my own changes. Stash allows to manage merge conflicts as well. You can use stash when you want to switch branches.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Github Acquisition</title>
      <link>/posts/microsoft-github-acquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/microsoft-github-acquisition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$7.5 billion is huge. A big part of that number includes value of open source projects. It is the open source projects that made Github what it is and brought the community together. Github made people recognize their potential, by having their work be shared and collaborated on an open, free platform.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$7.5 billion is huge. Microsoft paid good money for this acquisition. I do not know what the ultimate goal is here, but it is an investment into the future of Github, and I am cautiously optimistic - just like a lot of people.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$7.5 billion is huge. Github is built on Ruby on Rails, which is an open source framework. Github is a Hub for Git (get it!). Git is an open source version control system.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$7.5 billion is huge. A note on Ruby on Rails - It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what you use as long as you get the task done. In case of Github, it is Ruby on Rails. If you remember Trello ($425 million acquisition by Atlassian), its a jQuery Drag and Drop app. In the beginning, tools dont have to be the fastest. Tools have to just work. You can worry about speed later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$7.5 billion is just huge. That is all.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Merge</title>
      <link>/posts/how-i-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-i-merge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stage the files&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git add &amp;lt;files&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commit the files&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git commit -m &amp;#34;&amp;lt;message subject&amp;gt;&amp;#34; -m &amp;#34;&amp;lt;message body, if needed&amp;gt;&amp;#34;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pull the master&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git pull origin master&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Merge any conflicts and commit. Then,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git push origin master&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Profit!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook</title>
      <link>/posts/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined facebook in 2007. Before that, I used to interact with friends on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orkut&#34;&gt;Orkut&lt;/a&gt;. I joined facebook because my friends told me to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Facebook was quite innocent when I joined. I was friends with people on Facebook that I was friends in real life, and I would see them every now and then, if not more. Then pages came along, and I started liking facebook pages. Friends started to invite me to like a page, and I would do the same. People started sharing articles, news, from sources that were not always credible. Cookies started tracking information everywhere outside of facebook. Facebook made it super easy to share any web page on facebook - there is a button on top of this page to do the same. Apps started using facebook as a login, and in return for the convenience of not having to create another username and password, that you have to remember, we happily agreed to share our facebook profile with apps. Games that looked innocent on the surface asked for permission to use our facebook data, and post on the wall on our behalf, and we happily, explicitly, gave consent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longing for a consumer upgradable Macbook Pro</title>
      <link>/posts/longing-for-a-consumer-upgradable-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/longing-for-a-consumer-upgradable-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first Macbook was a 2011 Macbook Pro &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/kb/SP619?locale=en_US&#34;&gt;(MC700LL/A)&lt;/a&gt;. It came with a 4GB of RAM and 320 GB HDD. After 1.5 years of use, I was able to upgrade the RAM to 8GB and swap out the HDD for a 512 GB SSD. The performance upgrade was life changing. The effort was minimal. Just unscrew the back panel using a precision philips screwdriver and with little knowledge, one can swap out the RAM and HDD/SSD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I switched to Ghost</title>
      <link>/posts/i-switched-to-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/i-switched-to-ghost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I switched to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;ghost&lt;/a&gt;. If you go to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://anurag.codes/52-posts-in-52-weeks-atleast/&#34;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about how I wanted to use posthaven and how it is great.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am using posthaven over medium, or blogger, or wordpress, is because of its simplicity. You can read much about posthaven here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthaven.com/&#34;&gt;https://posthaven.com/&lt;/a&gt; . It has an easy posting format, lets me use my own domain and I can even email my posts. I don’t have to think about it much. Its simple!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to not use an ad blocker</title>
      <link>/posts/when-to-not-use-an-ad-blocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-to-not-use-an-ad-blocker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use an ad-blocker on my browsers. Its called &lt;a href=&#34;https://adblockplus.org/&#34;&gt;ad-block plus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The good part of using an ad-blocker is that it blocks the ads on the sites I visit. It also helps with blocking malware, spam, and cookies that track over websites (you know how when you search for shoes on zappos and then that shoe ad shows up on every website you visit).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The bad part of using an ad-blocker is that there are websites that are solely run, or are majorly dependent on ad revenue. Such websites lose on that revenue when my ad-blocker instance blocks their ads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>52 posts in 52 weeks (atleast)</title>
      <link>/posts/52-posts-in-52-weeks-atleast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/52-posts-in-52-weeks-atleast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to do this for a while - blog. And by a while, I mean for years now. I try, and then I am not so comfortable about it, and things come up, and I give up. It is easy to give up. There is no direct immediate cost to giving up. There are other, easier things to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But why write? Why blog? Well because writing is a means of recording information. It is a means of sharing answers and solutions. It is at times cathartic and therapeutic. I could write all of this in a journal. Sharing in a blog format, hopefully, helps with getting constructive feedback on my ideas and thoughts. It hopefully helps people who may have had a similar issue that I have and find a solution here on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
